Annemarie Cates

Full Stack Developer

Pensacola, FL (850) 324-2445 acates910@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full stack developer, with six years of professional experience in front end web development and one year of experience in back end development. I have experience maintaining and adding functionality to web applications based on client needs. Specializing in client side programming, jQuery and responsive design.

EXPERIENCE

ACT Innovations

Gulf Breeze, FL - Software Developer

OCTOBER 2019 - CURRENT

- **Position:** Full stack developer providing maintenance on multiple applications relating to drug court and drug testing in northwest Florida.
 - Part of a three person development team, with the third person being the development team lead. We each work on front end and back end maintenance tickets assigned via Azure DevOps on multiple web applications. Tickets consist of adding logic and new functionality to parts of the application as well as altering and adding data to the database. When a ticket is complete, a pull request is sent, approved and merged into the shared repository. Agile/SCRUM Methodology is practiced.
 - Common technologies used: Visual Studio, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Git, SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, React, ASP.NET MVC, Razor Pages, JavaScript/jQuery.

UICGS / Bowhead Total Enterprise Solutions

Mobile, AL - Front End Developer

JANUARY 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

- Part of a 3 person development team on the TRACES contract.
 - The TRACES contract consists of a web application which was originally built by an outside company using C#/ASP.NET and Angular. Bowhead then took over this contract. The app belongs to our project manager located in Huntsville, AL. The TRACES applications primary purpose is project cost estimation.

- Our teams objective is to complete tasks on, deconstruct, modernize and update the existing TRACES application. The final goal being an application rewrite.
- Each team member works in a separate development environment on their private code repository of the app. At the end of the Sprint (each Sprint lasting 2 weeks,) each developer sends a pull request to the lead developer of the team via Azure DevOps for review and approval of their code. When approved, our code is merged together, goes through UAT and is then sent to the project owner to use their updated application.
- Agile/SCRUM methodology is used. This includes task assignment via Jira, daily stand up meetings with the team, daily stand-up notes via Confluence, requirements meetings with the project manager and travel to Huntsville, AL to meet with the project manager. Retrospectives and requirements meetings are held at the beginning of each Sprint. These meetings are led by the SCRUM master, our tasks are assigned and what is expected of us / priorities for the upcoming Sprint are communicated.
- Common technologies used: Visual Studio, VS Code, Git, Microsoft Azure,
 CLI, SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, Jira, Confluence, Angular, C#,
 VB.NET, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC and Razor Pages, Entity Framework.
- Writing: Part of my responsibility in this position includes writing evaluations of the TRACES application and its modules. These evaluations usually consist of outlining a case for the purpose of government approval, that way we can move forward with the plan for the application.
- Developed PHP website for Regional Sediment Management.

Smart Horizons (division of Darwin Global)

Pensacola, FL - Media Specialist

JANUARY 2016 - JUNE 2018

- Individual development of 100 plus interactive web based applications built using jQuery primarily. Applications falling into UI categories such as draggable/droppable, sortable, clickable, checkbox, graphs, forms etc.
 - Applications developed due to the conversion from Flash to HTML5/CSS/JS.
 - Applications are used for student testing/career training to test learned material at different points during a course.
 - Applications needed to have cross browser compatibility, have no conflicts when uploaded into the courseware player and be 100% responsive, as they would be used on tablet devices primarily.
- Developed HTML website for Premier Responder.
- Implementing newsletter design (HTML version/email version) and sending to contacts via Reachmail.

Audio editing using Audacity.

Footbridge Media

Pensacola, FL - Website Manager

OCTOBER 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2015

- Part of a 4 person team who managed and maintained over 1000 HTML, PHP and WordPress contractor websites monthly or at the client's request.
- Responsibilities:
 - **Graphic design** creating banners and coupons.
 - Adding/removing content badges, testimonials, pages, blog posts, content changes, content writing.
 - Search Engine Optimization adding Google Analytics, using Google Webmaster Tools (301 redirects) and following the checklist on Google Pagespeed Insights. Adding structured data, meta tags and keyword phrases.
 - Theme and layout changes.
 - Site inspections inspecting websites for errors as well as maintaining speed and content on a monthly basis without the client's request.

Say it by Song

Pensacola, FL - Creative Editor

JULY 2010 - FEBRUARY 2012

- Created 30 second multimedia messages containing clips of popular songs and their lyrics. Users could then share them with friends via text message and/or Facebook.
- Added and maintained content on the WordPress website.
- Used social media to gain a following, generate unique visitors on the website and increase the number of "song messages" shared daily.

EDUCATION

Pensacola State College, Pensacola, FL - Web Development Certificate

2012 - 2013

In progress. I am not currently taking classes.

SKILLS

Training/Certifications

- Confidential Security Clearance (Public Trust: Tier 1)
 - > March, 2019 October, 2019

- Azure DevOps Training
 - > 09/09/2019 09/12/2019 (in person)
- Angular Training on PluralSight
 - ➤ June, 2019 (5 hour course online)

Languages

HTML5, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries/Environments

Bootstrap, jQuery, Angular, React, Three.js, createJS, Laravel, Rails, Node.js, Express

Build Tools

NPM, Git

CMS

WordPress, Shopify, Joomla, Kona CMS, Pensanet

Software

Adobe Creative Suite CS3 - CC (Dreamweaver, Photoshop, After Effects), GIMP, Netbeans, Visual Studio 2015/2017, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text 3, SQL Server Data Tools, Audacity, FileZilla, Jira, Confluence

Operating Systems

Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X

Other

- ➤ Agile/SCRUM Methodology
- Responsive design
- ➤ Command Line Interface
- ➤ Browser Developer Tools
- > Font Awesome
- The ability to build a web presence (Concept, layout, programming and SEO)
- > Experience developing marketing strategies using social media.
- > Experience communicating technical concepts.
- > Problem solver with a passion for creating smart and efficient solutions.
- > Experience attending meetings and articulating my plan and progress.